The epic finale that will live forever.
The Twilight Saga: Breaking Dawn - Part 2 is a adventure,
fantasy, drama film directed by Bill Condon.
After the birth of Renesmee, the Cullens gather other vampire clans in order to protect the
child from a false allegation that puts the family in front of the Volturi.
Bella Swan, played by Kristen Stewart.
Edward Cullen, played by Robert Pattinson.
Jacob Black, played by Taylor Lautner.
Dr. Carlisle Cullen, played by Peter Facinelli.
Esme Cullen, played by Elizabeth Reaser.
Alice Cullen, played by Ashley Greene.
The Twilight Saga: Breaking Dawn – Part 2 is a 2012 American vampire romantic fantasy film,
directed by Bill Condon, and written by Melissa Rosenberg, based on the 2008 novel.
It is the fifth and final installment in the The Twilight Saga film series.
The film features Kristen Stewart, Robert Pattinson, and Taylor Lautner reprising their roles from the previous films, with the ensemble cast also including
Billy Burke, Peter Facinelli, Elizabeth Reaser, Kellan Lutz, Nikki Reed, Jackson Rathbone, Ashley Greene, Michael Sheen, and Dakota Fanning.
In the film, Bella, now a vampire, aligns with the Cullens, the werewolves, and other allies to
face the Volturi, who view her half-human, half-vampire child as a possible threat.
Summit Entertainment announced that Breaking Dawn would be
adapted into a two-part film on June 10, 2010.
Principal photography for both parts began on November
1, 2010, and wrapped on April 22, 2011.
The second part was shot in Baton Rouge, New Orleans and Vancouver.
The Twilight Saga: Breaking Dawn – Part 2 premiered at the Nokia Theatre in Los Angeles on November 12, 2012,
and was theatrically released in the United States on November 16, by Summit Entertainment.
The film received mixed reviews from critics and grossed $868 million, becoming the
sixth-highest-grossing film of 2012 and the highest-grossing of the series.
The film received eleven nominations at the 33rd Golden Raspberry
Awards and won seven, including Worst Picture.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book,
vampire, villainess, affectation, romance.
The tone is emotional.